

BILAL AL TAKI

Doctor Data Scientist and AI

- Mars 22, 1991 Française et Libanaise ★ 162 avenue paul vaillant couturier, 75014 Paris **3** +33 7 85 68 63 09
- bilal.altaki.math@gmail.com in LinkedIn altaki.github.io/HP/ GitHub

EDUCATION

PhD in applied mathematics **Grenoble-Alpes University**

2013 - 2016

Master degree in mathematics Lebanese University & **Nantes University**

2011 - 2013

CERTIFICATIONS

Here is a list of courses that I have accomplished on Coursera as a part of my interest in Data Science and AI fields.

• What is Data Science IBM.

(Syllabus, Certificate)

• Python for Data Science, AI & Development|IBM.

(Syllabus, Certificate)

• Data Science with Python IBM.

(Syllabus, Certificate)

• Machine Learning with Python.

(Syllabus, Certificate)

• Machine Learning Specialization|Stanford.

(Syllabus, Certificate)

STRENGTHS

Data Visualization Python Machine Learning Maple Tensorflow | Deeplearning Latex | Github | SQL

LANGUAGES

Arabic French **English**



ABOUT ME

Having a PhD in applied mathematics, and being passionate about Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning related subjects with medium knowledge in this field, I am excited to apply my skills for solving real-world problems. Currently, I am a visiting Researcher at TU Kaiserslautern.

SKILLS

- · Project management.
- Extraction and structuring of data.
- Development of artificial intelligence algorithms.
- Industrialization of artificial intelligence models in applications.
- Following latest advancements.

EXPERIENCE

Research and Teaching Fellow | Sorbonne University

Sept 2021 - Aug 2022 Paris, FR

Researcher | Peking University

i Jan 2020 - Aug 2021 Beijing, CH

Research and Teaching Fellow | Sorbonne University

a Jan 2019 - Aug 2019 Paris, FR

Researcher | INRIA

Sept 2017 - Dec 2018 Paris, FR

More details about my research and teaching activities? click here!

PROJECTS

Here is a list of projects that I have done as a part of self-training on Data Science.

Data Science with Python | Q 2022

The aim of this project is to fit a linear regression or a Ridge Regression model to predict the price using the list of features given on a dataset which contains house sale prices for King County.

Machine Learning with Python | • 2022

In this project, we use classification models such as K Nearest Neighbor(KNN), Decision Tree, Support Vector Machine, or Logistic Regression to determine whether a loan is paid off or in based on a dataset about past loans.

Car's generation detection | 2022

The aim of this project is to predict the generation (I or II) of some unknown generation cars based on the features of each generation.